<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?><feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" ><generator uri="https://jekyllrb.com/" version="3.9.0">Jekyll</generator><link href="http://localhost:4000/feed.xml" rel="self" type="application/atom+xml" /><link href="http://localhost:4000/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" /><updated>2023-07-24T17:09:10-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/feed.xml</id><title type="html">Brigitte Castañeda</title><subtitle>Personal website.
</subtitle><entry><title type="html">Can growth take place while reducing emissions?</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-1/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Can growth take place while reducing emissions?" /><published>2023-05-15T16:11:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T16:11:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-1</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-1/">&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/7g7P.gif&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Stephen showing off. 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;This study aims to determine &lt;i&gt;whether the economic effect of introducing a carbon tax differs between countries, according to the energy mix&lt;i&gt; of clean and polluting inputs. Following a model of directed technical change and environmental, I empirically analyze the implementation of a carbon tax in countries with different carbon-intensity energy sources and the allocation of revenues. I find four main results: (i) In the absence of subsidies, carbon taxes have a negative effect on economic growth, (ii) this negative effect is a decreasing function of the proportion of clean energy sources in the energy mix increases. (iii) subsidies for clean inputs have a positive effect on economic growth, and (iv) the magnitude of this effect grows with the proportion of clean energy sources. These results are consistent with the predictions of the theoretical model and suggest that policymakers could consider this relationship between the energy mix and the economic effect of a carbon tax when creating environmental regulations. &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bNTOP0Q08lJpOr-MEamFc9shRYE6NCLn/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;See Paper&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;The main findings provide empirical evidence on the relationship between carbon tax implementation and economic growth, highlighting the importance of considering the composition of energy sources in the analysis.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/Resultado_umbrales_.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Effect of the carbon tax at different thresholds of the participation of energy sources.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lessons-learned&quot;&gt;Lessons learned&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Implementing a carbon tax is associated with an increase in the GDP growth rate in the early years of the climate policy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The effect of the carbon tax on GDP growth varies depending on the composition of the energy matrix. In countries with a high share of carbon-intensive energy sources, the carbon tax is associated with a reduction in the growth rate. In countries with a high share of clean energy sources, the carbon tax is associated with an increase in the growth rate.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The magnitude of the effect of the carbon tax on GDP growth varies depending on the model specification used. The estimated effects range from 0.6 to 1.5 percentage points in the year after implementing the policy.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;The effect of the carbon tax on employment rate is not statistically significant in the first three years after the policy.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html">Stephen showing off.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">REDD+, deforestación y cultivos ilícitos.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-redd/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="REDD+, deforestación y cultivos ilícitos." /><published>2023-05-15T16:11:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-15T16:11:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-redd</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-redd/">&lt;p class=&quot;cursive-text&quot;&gt;Con: Carolina Castro, Santiago Herrera, María Alejandra Vélez.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/redd.jpg&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Foto desde Miramar, Bahía Málaga, Colombia.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;La mayoría de los análisis sobre los impactos de REDD+ se enfocan en su eficiencia para evitar o reducir  la deforestación. En este estudio, además de examinar su &lt;i&gt;‘efecto en la deforestación’&lt;/i&gt;, se explora su &lt;i&gt;‘efecto en el control de la expansión de los cultivos ilícitos’&lt;/i&gt; para el caso de los &lt;a href=&quot;https://data-agenciadetierras.opendata.arcgis.com/maps/4f602976504c43ce86c470cac0443e8b/about&quot;&gt;consejos comunitarios de comunidades negras&lt;/a&gt; en el Pacífico Colombiano.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Este caso es relevante pues según estudios previos, la titulación colectiva a comunidades negras ha disminuido la deforestación y porque allí se encuentra el 20% de los cultivos ilícitos del país. Este estudio busca entender &lt;i&gt;si la firma de acuerdos REDD+ por parte de los consejos comunitarios, además de la gobernanza colectiva, refuerza los sistemas de monitoreo y mejora las condiciones económicas para evitar la expansión de economías  ilícitas además de reducir la deforestación&lt;i&gt;. A través del uso de información satelital y herramientas econométricas, se encontró una relación causal entre la firma de los proyectos REDD+ y la reducción de los cultivos ilícitos durante los primeros años de implementación. Sin embargo, no se encontraron efectos significativos en la deforestación. Se evidencia que proyectos de conservación ambiental como los proyectos REDD+ pueden hacer frente a la expansión de cultivos ilícitos en el corto plazo y son una herramienta para distribuir los costos de la conservación.&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;proyecto-en-desarrollo-será-presentado-en-17th-biennial-conference-of-the-international-society-for-ecological-economics&quot;&gt;Proyecto en desarrollo, será presentado en &lt;a href=&quot;https://theisee.wildapricot.org/event-5112431&quot;&gt;17th Biennial Conference of the International Society for Ecological Economics&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html">Con: Carolina Castro, Santiago Herrera, María Alejandra Vélez.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Pancake</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/pancake/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Pancake" /><published>2023-05-01T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-05-01T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/pancake</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/pancake/">&lt;p&gt;[TODO]&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html">[TODO]</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Impacto fiscal de las regalías en los municipios de Colombia.</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-regalias/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Impacto fiscal de las regalías en los municipios de Colombia." /><published>2023-04-15T16:11:00-04:00</published><updated>2023-04-15T16:11:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-regalias</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2023/article-regalias/">&lt;p class=&quot;cursive-text&quot;&gt;Coautoria con: Andrés Álvarez y Marc Hofstetter.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/regalias_1.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Distribución de regalías antes y después de la reforma de 2012.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;En el presente estudio se evalúa &lt;i&gt;el efecto de la reforma al Sistema General de Regalías en 2012, sobre los ingresos tributarios municipales en Colombia&lt;i&gt;. Para estudiar los efectos en las finanzas regionales de una posible reducción de los ingresos de regalías, nos preguntamos qué tanta dependencia fiscal ha provocado estos ingresos de actividades extractivas en las regiones. La literatura se ha enfocado principalmente en estudiar la alta dependencia de las regiones productoras, que eran las que históricamente han recibido mayores ingresos de esta naturaleza, y cuyas economías son más dependientes del sector minero. Sin embargo, Colombia realizado desde 2012, una serie de reformas de distribución de las regalías, buscando que estos ingresos le lleguen a los municipios no productores, dirigiendo mayores recursos aquellos municipios con mayores necesidades básicas insatisfechas.&lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1bNTOP0Q08lJpOr-MEamFc9shRYE6NCLn/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;See WP&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/i&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;En la Ilustración 2 se puede ver el detalle de la forma en que se distribuyen los municipios que se clasificaron como ganadores, perdedores y neutros ante el cambio en la distribución de las regalías de 2012. Se puede ver cómo las regalías ganan en importancia dentro de los ingresos de los municipios ganadores y cómo caen considerablemente para los municipios perdedores.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/regalias_2.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Municipios ganadores, perdedores y neutros con la reforma de 2012- Grupos de tratamiento y de control.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;lecciones-aprendidas&quot;&gt;Lecciones aprendidas&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;Reducción en el esfuerzo fiscal de los municipios ganadores. Disminución del recaudo tributario en un 37.6% menos que en los neutros.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;No se presenta un incremento equivalente en el esfuerzo fiscal de los municipios perdedores.&lt;/li&gt;
    &lt;li&gt;La transición energética requerirá entonces un esfuerzo mayor para diversificar los ingresos municipales, no solo en los municipios históricamente productores sino tambien en los municipios con necesidades basicas insatisfechas (más vulnerables).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;hr /&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="article" /><summary type="html">Coautoria con: Andrés Álvarez y Marc Hofstetter.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Equity index for educational scores standardization</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/data-ds4a/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Equity index for educational scores standardization" /><published>2020-08-21T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-21T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/data-ds4a</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/data-ds4a/">&lt;p&gt;Below I summarize the final project of the Data Science for All &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.correlation-one.com/es-co/data-science-for-all-colombia&quot;&gt;DS4A&lt;/a&gt; Course, 2020. Carried out by team 41, with Alejandra Martínez, Gabriel Cárdenas, Sebastián Betancourt. Under guidance of TAs: Daniel Gil , Chris Earle. &lt;a href=&quot;https://drive.google.com/file/d/1X2q5-K7NWpWDCZYJm2HKSxyt0Nn6PKGz/view?usp=sharing&quot;&gt;See Report&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;background&quot;&gt;Background&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Education enables upward socioeconomic mobility and is a key to escaping poverty. Over the past decade, major progress was made towards increasing access to education and school enrollment rates. Nevertheless the Saber 11 exam scores have a strong dependency on the socioeconomic background of the students, so comparing them using the same scale will put certain students at an advantage that other students don’t have access to.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Our proposal is to create a scaled index based on socioeconomic variables, which will offset the score of those students with a higher than expected score and deduct those with a lower than expected score.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/equatyindex.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Percentage of student participation in the Saber 11 exam and the best scores, in 2019 according to their socioeconomic strata. 
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;model&quot;&gt;Model&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;To test our hypothesis, we used Clustering techniques to generate 3 groups using only the socioeconomic variables, and then, we check how the Scores changed along each of the groups.This three clusters are a good representation of low, medium and high socioeconomic background.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/equatyindex_1.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Clusters&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/equatyindex_2.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Expected results&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col two caption&quot;&gt;
    Song&apos;s journey
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;proposed-equity-index&quot;&gt;Proposed equity index&lt;/h4&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Expected Scores were calculated for each individual, comparing several regression techniques and selecting the one that performs better in the data. The selected algorithm was a Linear Regression with ElasticNet Regularization, and the expected scores were used to calculate the index for each student, used to scale its original score as follows.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;\(Index = \frac{Actual Score}{Expected Score}\)
\(Adjusted Score = Actual Score * Index\)&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 id=&quot;results&quot;&gt;Results&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;As a solution to the existing gap in access to higher education, this equity indicator was created to compensate those students who excelled with scores higher than the expected score according to our model results.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;When selecting the best students using this index, it is observed that the best students of each cluster (socioeconomic group) would have the privilege of accessing more benefits, such as scholarships to access university.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/equatyindex_3.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row center&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img src=&quot;/assets/img/equatyindex_4.png&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html">Below I summarize the final project of the Data Science for All DS4A Course, 2020. Carried out by team 41, with Alejandra Martínez, Gabriel Cárdenas, Sebastián Betancourt. Under guidance of TAs: Daniel Gil , Chris Earle. See Report</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Hello World (Again)</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/code/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Hello World (Again)" /><published>2020-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-08-09T00:00:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/code</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/code/">&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Competitive Programming has always been one of my passions, although not a reciprocating one. It was around 2010 when I first heard about it at my university. What started as an authentic journey towards constant Rejected or TLE, turned into a remarkable opportunity to make great friendships and improve my problem-solving skills, which in retrospect shaped most of my later choices in life.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;One of my New Year’s resolutions, perhaps influenced by extended conversations with an outstanding programmer and food addict, was to improve my competitive programming skills by investing a considerable amount of time studying algorithms from a theoretical and practical point of view.  Consequently, as a metric of improvement, I considered no other than the renowned Russian competitive programming platform &lt;a href=&quot;https://codeforces.com/&quot;&gt;Codeforces&lt;/a&gt;.  My ambitious hope: to become purple ranked (&amp;gt;1900 ELO). Only time will tell, yet I will use this &lt;a href=&quot;https://github.com/Alfo5123/CodeTrain&quot;&gt;repository&lt;/a&gt; to track my progress.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;figure class=&quot;highlight&quot;&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;code class=&quot;language-c--&quot; data-lang=&quot;c++&quot;&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;cp&quot;&gt;#include&amp;lt;bits/stdc++.h&amp;gt;
&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;using&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;namespace&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;n&quot;&gt;std&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;

&lt;span class=&quot;kt&quot;&gt;int&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;nf&quot;&gt;main&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;()&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;{&lt;/span&gt;
    &lt;span class=&quot;k&quot;&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class=&quot;mi&quot;&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;;&lt;/span&gt;
&lt;span class=&quot;p&quot;&gt;}&lt;/span&gt;&lt;/code&gt;&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/figure&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="programming" /><summary type="html">Competitive Programming has always been one of my passions, although not a reciprocating one. It was around 2010 when I first heard about it at my university. What started as an authentic journey towards constant Rejected or TLE, turned into a remarkable opportunity to make great friendships and improve my problem-solving skills, which in retrospect shaped most of my later choices in life.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Cuerda</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/cuerda/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Cuerda" /><published>2020-05-14T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/cuerda</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/cuerda/">&lt;p style=&quot;color:black; font-size: 100%; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;La quebradiza cuerda,   &lt;br /&gt;
a la que nos sujetamos como a la vida, &lt;br /&gt;
sostiene con firmeza un elefante herido&lt;br /&gt;
que no sabe, ni sabrá, como llegó ahí;&lt;br /&gt;
y con las manos desgarradas soportamos&lt;br /&gt;
aquel despreciable e incesante llanto&lt;br /&gt;
que el dolor sabe producir en la criatura.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p style=&quot;color:black; font-size: 100%; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Ya es muy tarde, no hay vuelta atrás, &lt;br /&gt;
¿no será el regalo de algún dios envidioso?&lt;br /&gt;
¿por qué no sólo taparse los oídos y caminar?&lt;br /&gt;
La resistencia a la que nos acostumbramos, &lt;br /&gt;
abraza nuestra tristeza y nos ciega lentamente&lt;br /&gt;
Sólo espero algún día llegar a creer&lt;br /&gt;
que si seguimos aquí, es por culpa de la cuerda.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">La quebradiza cuerda, a la que nos sujetamos como a la vida, sostiene con firmeza un elefante herido que no sabe, ni sabrá, como llegó ahí; y con las manos desgarradas soportamos aquel despreciable e incesante llanto que el dolor sabe producir en la criatura. Ya es muy tarde, no hay vuelta atrás, ¿no será el regalo de algún dios envidioso? ¿por qué no sólo taparse los oídos y caminar? La resistencia a la que nos acostumbramos, abraza nuestra tristeza y nos ciega lentamente Sólo espero algún día llegar a creer que si seguimos aquí, es por culpa de la cuerda.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Bienvenido</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/bievenido/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Bienvenido" /><published>2020-05-14T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-05-14T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/bievenido</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/bievenido/">&lt;p style=&quot;color:black; font-size: 100%; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Quiero aprender a creer&lt;br /&gt;
que el tiempo no ha errado,&lt;br /&gt;
que cada estrella conmigo&lt;br /&gt;
de ti el sol no ha alejado.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:black; font-size: 100%; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Debo enseñarme a fingir,  &lt;br /&gt;
que la distancia no se mide,&lt;br /&gt;
que la confianza no limita&lt;br /&gt;
y que el corazón no decide.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:black; font-size: 100%; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Ayer las palabras fueron &lt;br /&gt;
alas de un afán prematuro, &lt;br /&gt;
deseando dejar el suelo&lt;br /&gt;
cuando caminar era seguro.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p style=&quot;color:black; font-size: 100%; text-align: center;&quot;&gt;Hoy los sentidos nos quitan&lt;br /&gt;
lo que la intuición nos dejó,&lt;br /&gt;
como el ocaso de esa risa&lt;br /&gt;
cuando la razón se alejó.&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="poetry" /><summary type="html">Quiero aprender a creer que el tiempo no ha errado, que cada estrella conmigo de ti el sol no ha alejado.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">New beginning</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/new-beginning/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="New beginning" /><published>2020-04-21T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-21T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/new-beginning</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/new-beginning/">&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;col three&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/guitar.jpeg&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Guitar&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Side effects of having an amazing girlfriend. Yes, a Martin Acoustic-Electric Guitar.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-justify&quot; id=&quot;how-to-easily-start-again-in-music-after-a-long-break&quot;&gt;How to easily start again in music after a long break?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Get access to the instrument you loved.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Embrace depression. You can always practice scales meanwhile.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Realize &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=aS1esgRV4Rc&quot;&gt;how essential art is in life&lt;/a&gt;. Avoid forgetting that life is more than work.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Find places where you have never felt lost before. Both, inside and outside.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Keep learning music theory. Books, classical music, friends, everything counts.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Seize the opportunity of isolation. Any pandemic scenario can help.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Take the best from those occasional and brief creative moments.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Listen to music you would not “normally” include in your playlist.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Share your progress with a close group of people you trust. Bore them with your multiple records until they start disagreeing.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Let multiple friends recommend you Garage Band. Don’t listen to them immediately. Regret it later. Enjoy the learning curve.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;
    &lt;p&gt;Understand how little you know.&lt;/p&gt;
  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;p&gt;You can find here some of my recent attempts. Excluding Garden of Eden, which is a cover, the rest is original work.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/765569443&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512&quot; title=&quot;Alfredo De la Fuente&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Alfredo De la Fuente&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512/times&quot; title=&quot;Times&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Times&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/783363727&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512&quot; title=&quot;Alfredo De la Fuente&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Alfredo De la Fuente&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512/garden-of-eden&quot; title=&quot;Garden Of Eden&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Garden Of Eden&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;100&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/778712911&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512&quot; title=&quot;Alfredo De la Fuente&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Alfredo De la Fuente&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512/komorebi&quot; title=&quot;Komorebi&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Komorebi&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="music" /><summary type="html">Side effects of having an amazing girlfriend. Yes, a Martin Acoustic-Electric Guitar.</summary></entry><entry><title type="html">Meraki</title><link href="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/meraki/" rel="alternate" type="text/html" title="Meraki" /><published>2020-04-21T11:12:00-04:00</published><updated>2020-04-21T11:12:00-04:00</updated><id>http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/meraki</id><content type="html" xml:base="http://localhost:4000/articles/2020/meraki/">&lt;iframe width=&quot;100%&quot; height=&quot;200&quot; scrolling=&quot;no&quot; frameborder=&quot;no&quot; allow=&quot;autoplay&quot; src=&quot;https://w.soundcloud.com/player/?url=https%3A//api.soundcloud.com/tracks/856387372&amp;amp;color=%23ff5500&amp;amp;auto_play=false&amp;amp;hide_related=false&amp;amp;show_comments=true&amp;amp;show_user=true&amp;amp;show_reposts=false&amp;amp;show_teaser=true&amp;amp;visual=true&quot;&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
&lt;div style=&quot;font-size: 10px; color: #cccccc;line-break: anywhere;word-break: normal;overflow: hidden;white-space: nowrap;text-overflow: ellipsis; font-family: Interstate,Lucida Grande,Lucida Sans Unicode,Lucida Sans,Garuda,Verdana,Tahoma,sans-serif;font-weight: 100;&quot;&gt;&lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512&quot; title=&quot;Alfredo De la Fuente&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Alfredo De la Fuente&lt;/a&gt; · &lt;a href=&quot;https://soundcloud.com/alfredo-de-la-fuente512/meraki&quot; title=&quot;Meraki&quot; target=&quot;_blank&quot; style=&quot;color: #cccccc; text-decoration: none;&quot;&gt;Meraki&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Probably one of the most productive Junes I have ever had, despite my close encounter with death.
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;br /&gt;&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Truth be told, the idea of composing a song from scratch in a month still resonates as crazy to me. Nobody warns you how challenging it could be. Yet I enjoyed every single part of it. Despite I did not know where it was heading most of times, suddenly pieces started to fit and inspiration played its role: it started to sound like a song.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;Just as Dante was kindly guided through the circles of Hell by Virgil, I should deeply thank &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.instagram.com/eliza.carrington/&quot;&gt;Eliza Carrington&lt;/a&gt; for her guitar/composition lessons and songwriting advices, which made possible this crazy song idea I had. It worths mentioning, she happens to be an &lt;a href=&quot;https://www.youtube.com/channel/UCslUnS2O1EMLiJPeRDXksMQ&quot;&gt;amazing singer, songwriter and guitarist&lt;/a&gt; and I feel lucky to learn from her experience and perspective.&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;h4 class=&quot;text-justify&quot; id=&quot;what-did-i-learn&quot;&gt;What did I learn?&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Do not understimate the power of secondary dominants.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;The balance between tension and resolution is key.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Explore imagery and metaphors in conveying emotional lyrics.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Adding a sad piano, choir, or odd drums could lead to interesting ideas.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Avoiding predictability by incorporating variations and arrangements.&lt;/li&gt;
  &lt;li&gt;Enjoying the process itself is the best reward.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;

&lt;div class=&quot;img_row&quot;&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/MerakiWriting.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Lyrics&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/LyricsMeraki.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Chord Progression&quot; /&gt;
    &lt;img class=&quot;col one&quot; src=&quot;/assets/img/MerakiProduction.png&quot; alt=&quot;&quot; title=&quot;Mixing&quot; /&gt;
&lt;/div&gt;
&lt;div class=&quot;col three caption&quot;&gt;
    Song&apos;s journey
&lt;/div&gt;

&lt;p class=&quot;text-justify&quot;&gt;I need to apologize to all my close friends who were almost emotionally forced to listen to my endless song drafts and providing me valuable feedback. You are the best!&lt;/p&gt;

&lt;p&gt;Hopefully this is only the start :)&lt;/p&gt;</content><author><name></name></author><category term="idea" /><category term="music" /><summary type="html">Alfredo De la Fuente · Meraki</summary></entry></feed>